Guide to the Lester Wunderman Papers, 1946-2010 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Administrative Files, 1952-1999 and undated, (17 boxes)
  - Publicity, 1964-2010
    - Interviews
      - Home Team Magazine (AT&T house publication), 1980 (Box 16)
      - Investors Business Daily, 1999 Jan. (Box 16)
      - Marilyn Berger (television), 1980 Jan. (Box 16)
      - Mark Strook, for an oral history of Young & Rubicam, 1994 (Box 16)
      - Marketing Direct (France), 1995 Nov.-Dec. (Box 17)
      - [Marketing Magazine (Canada), 1995 Nov.: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV4] (Box 17)
      - Médias (France, text in French), 1983 Jan. 14-Feb. 3 (Box 17)
      - Stratégies, 1980 May, (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV4) (Box 17)
      - Stratégies, 1992 Oct. 23, (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV4) (Box 17)
      - Telemarketing Journal, 1994 apr. (Box 17)
      - [Wunderama, 1997 May: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV4] (Box 17)
    - Press conference, 1996 (Box 17)
    - Profiles
      - Adweek 20th anniversary issue, 1998 Nov. (Box 17)
      - Ganz Direkt! 95/96 (Germany), 1995 (Box 17)
      - Madison Avenue, by Henry Lee (with folder of comments), 1964-1965 (Box 17)
      - Sales and Marketing Management 80th anniversary issue, 1998 Oct. (Box 17)
    - Retirement announcement, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-1998, (8 folders) (Box 17)
  - Samples of Direct Marketing Items, 1955-1998
    [Not every item produced by Wunderman]
    - [American Express, 1989: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV6] (Box 17)
    - [American Recording Society, circa 1951: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV6] (Box 17)
    - AT&T, 1988-1989 (Box 18)
    - Bethany Press, circa 1980s (Box 18)
    - Bristol-Myers Softique, 1964 (Box 18)
    - [Baron Philippe de Rothschild SA, 1976: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV6] (Box 18)
    - [Champion Papers, 1980: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV6] (Box 18)
    - Columbia House record club, 1963-1964, 1998, (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV6) (Box 18)
    - Diners Club (Britain), 1969-1971, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Direct Mail Advertising Association (produced by J. Walter Thompson Company), circa 1960s (Box 18)
    - [Encyclopedia Americana, 1962: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV5] (Box 18)
    - [Famous Artists School, 1957: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV6] (Box 18)
    - [Famous Writers School, 1960-1961: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV6], (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Ford, 1964 (Box 18)
    - Gevalia Kaffe, 1988-1989 (Box 18)
    - Holt, Rinehart & Winston, 1967 (Box 18)
    - [Hydromix (Doggett-Pfeil Co.), Maxwell Sackheim agency, circa 1940s: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV10] (Box 18)
    - IBM, 1970s (Box 18)
    - Jackson-Perkins, circa 1960s (Box 18)
    - Lincoln-Mercury (including Merkur Scorpio), 1988-1989, (4 folders; 3 folders removed to Oversize Materials) (Box 18)
    - [Literary Guild, 1967-1969: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV7], (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Mailbag, 1963 (Box 18)
    - McGovern-Shriver campaign, 1972 (Box 18)
    - National Observer Correspondence Schools (see also Famous Artists School and Famous Writers School in Oversize Materials), circa 1960 (Box 18)
    - New York Times
      - How to Make Your Advertising Produce (Book of the Month Club), 1956 (Box 18)
      - Successful Mail Order Selling, circa 1955 (Box 18)
    - P.J. Carroll & Company (Carroll Journals), 1988 (Box 18)
    - Schick Safety Razor Company, circa 1950s (Box 18)
    - Thomas Garraway Ltd., 1988 (Box 18)
    - [Time-Life Books, 1964-1965, 1989: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV7] (Box 18)
    - Vitasafe, 1958 (Box 18)
    - Various products coupon package, 1963 (Box 18)
- Speeches, 1957-2007, (24 boxes)
  Includes text of speeches, handwritten or typed drafts, alternate versions, and idea files, along with some correspondence and itineraries relating to speaking engagements. Arranged chronologically.
  - Speech File, 1961-1997
    [Consists of an organized set of typed speech texts in chronological order]
    - List of speeches, 1961-1997 (Box 19)
    - 1961 Oct. 1, Speech to Hundred Million Club, New York (Box 19)
    - 1967 Mar. 3, Mail Order: The Coming Revolution in Marketing, Advertising Club of New York (Box 19)
    - 1967 June 8, Newspapers: A Dynamic Direct Response Medium, American Association of Newspaper Representatives (Box 19)
    - 1967 Nov. 29, Direct Marketing: The New Revolution in Selling, American Management Association at MIT, Cambridge Mass. (Box 19)
    - 1968 May 7, International Opportunities in Direct Marketing, Institut de Recherches et d'Etudes Publicitaires Group, Paris (Box 19)
    - 1968 Sept. 19, Address to Business Mail Day, Kansas City (Box 19)
    - 1969 Jan. 21, Advertising and the National Observer, National Observer Sales Meeting (Box 19)
    - 1969 Oct. 7, Address to National Association of Direct Mail Writers, New York (Box 19)
    - 1970 Feb. 7, From Ideas to Results, All-Florida Advertising Day, Clearwater (Box 19)
    - 1970 Apr. 1, Corporate Strategy for the 70s, American Book Publishers Council seminar, Tarrytown (Box 19)
    - 1971 Jan. 26, Direct Mail: A New Medium in a Changing Society, British DMA, London (Box 19)
    - 1971 Mar. 31, Direct Marketing: New Ways to Market in a Changing Society, Direct Marketing Day, New York (Box 19)
    - 1972 Mar. 14, Direct Marketing in the Seventies, New York University, New York (Box 19)
    - 1974 Apr. 24, Direct Marketing in a Changing Environment, Zurich (Box 19)
    - 1976 Jan. 21, Current Innovations and New Problems in Direct Marketing, Montreal (Box 19)
    - 1977 Jan. 10, Address to American Association of Nurserymen, Chicago (Box 19)
    - 1977 Mar. 2, Creativity in Advertising, Munich (Box 19)
    - 1980 Apr. 23, Frontiers of Direct Marketing, 12th International Direct Marketing Symposium, Montreux (speech and printed booklet) (Box 19)
    - 1982 Sept. 17, The Future Is Here and It Will Get Worse, Business Industrial Council, New York (Box 19)
    - 1983 Jan. 21, Data-Based Targeting Advertising--a New Age of Marketing Relevance, Adcraft Club, Detroit (Box 19)
    - 1984 May 2, Business-to-Business Direct Marketing, Worldwide Postmasters, Montreux (Box 19)
    - 1984 Oct. 24, Direct Marketing in the Year 2000, Presentation to FTC, Washington DC (Box 19)
    - 1984 Nov. 2, Frontiers of Direct Marketing II, Direct Marketing Seminar, Dublin (Box 19)
    - 1985 Oct. 25, Direct Marketing: A Many Splendored Thing, Direct Marketing Week, Milan (Box 19)
    - 1986 May 21, The Future of Direct Marketing, Touche Ross Electronic Shopping '86, Orlando (Box 19)
    - 1986 May 29, New Trends in Direct Marketing, British DMA, London (Box 19)
    - 1986 June 3, The Emerging Business of Direct Marketing, Direct Marketing Association Strategic Forum on Direct Marketing, Deauville (Box 19)
    - 1987 Jan. 26, The Worldwide Explosion of Direct Marketing, Japan Airlines Executive Group, Tokyo (Box 19)
    - 1987 Apr. 2, Direct Marketing and Its Future, Lester Wunderman Instituut, Amsterdam (Box 19)
    - 1988 May 18, Mail and the Media Revolution, National Postal Forum, Los Angeles (Box 19)
    - 1988 May 26, New Frontiers of Direct Marketing, AVPC Annual Symposium, San Sebastian (Box 19)
    - 1988 Sept. 27, The Expanding World of Direct Marketing, National Postal Forum, Washington DC (Box 19)
    - 1988 Nov. 28, New Frontiers of Direct Marketing, 20th Direct Marketing Congress, Wiesbaden (Box 19)
    - 1989, The New Age of Television Has Just Begun (Box 19)
    - 1989 Jan. 31, Image and Direct Marketing, La Semaine Europeenne du Direct Marketing, Paris (Box 19)
    - 1989 Jan. 31, The Changing World of Direct Marketing, La Semaine Europeenne du Direct Marketing, Paris (Box 19)
    - 1989 Jan. 31, The Frontiers of Direct Marketing III, La Semaine Europeenne du Direct Marketing, Paris (Box 19)
    - 1989 Mar. 3, The Price of Silence, Direct Marketing Day, New York (Box 19)
    - 1990 Sept. 21, Direct Marketing in Eastern Europe and the USSR, Direct Marketing in Eastern Europe and the USSR Conference, London (Box 19)
    - 1992 Nov. 16, Action Marketing: The Next Frontier, 15th Direct Marketing Week, London (Box 20)
    - 1993 Oct. 25, New Frontiers of Direct Marketing IV, Direct Marketing Association, Toronto (includes booklet form) (Box 20)
    - 1995 Apr. 19, Direct Marketing and Television: Past, Present and Future, Direct Response TV Expo Conference, Los Angeles (Box 20)
    - 1995 Sept. 13, Which Way to the Future?, DMIX, New York (Box 20)
    - 1995 Nov. 1, The World of Direct Mail: Past, Present and Future, Postal Conference, Toronto (Box 20)
    - 1996 May 13, Which Way to the Future II, Arrowwood (Box 20)
    - 1996 Oct. 29, Which Way to the Future?, Direct Marketing Association, New Orleans (Box 20)
    - 1997 May 13, Back to the Future, Baden-Baden (Box 20)
  - Speeches, 1957-2007
    - 1957-1961, Miscellaneous speeches and correspondence (Box 20)
    - Circa 1961, Creativity (Box 20)
    - 1961, Speeches and correspondence (Box 20)
    - 1963, American Association of Advertising Agencies, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - 1964, Terre Haute speech (Box 20)
    - 1964 Mar., Press Club--Ogilvy Book Day (Box 20)
    - 1964 Apr., American Heritage Executive Group (Box 20)
    - 1964 May, Direct Mail Advertising Association, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - 1965 Apr., New School (Box 21)
    - 1966 Sept., Grolier Salesmen (Box 21)
    - 1966-1970, Speech idea file (Box 21)
    - 1967 Jan., Bureau of Advertising Group (Box 21)
    - 1967 Mar., Advertising Club of New York, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - 1967 May, Direct Mail Day (Box 21)
    - 1967 June, American Association of Newspaper Representatives, (3 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 21)
    - 1967 Oct., American Association of Advertising Agencies Eastern Conference (Box 21)
    - 1967 Nov., American Marketing Association, MIT, (2 folders) (Box 21)
      [Speech where Wunderman lays out his philosophy of direct marketing.]
    - 1967-1968, Speech idea file (Box 21)
    - 1968 Feb., Boston University (Box 22)
    - 1968 Mar., Direct Mail Advertising Association, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - 1968 May, Paris speech, (3 folders) (Box 22)
    - 1968 Sept., Kansas City Business Mail Day (Box 22)
    - 1969 Jan., National Observer (Box 22)
    - 1969 Oct., National Association of Direct Mail Writers (Box 22)
    - 1970 Feb., All-Florida Advertising Day, Clearwater (Box 22)
    - 1970 Apr., American Book Publishers, Tarrytown (Box 23)
    - 1970 July, Columbia Records, Word of Mouth (Box 23)
    - 1971, Comments on speeches by others (Box 23)
    - 1971 Jan., British Direct Mail Advertising Association, (3 folders) (Box 23)
    - 1971 Feb.-Apr., Direct Marketing Day, New York, (6 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 23)
    - 1972 Mar., New York University, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - 1973 Nov., Time-Life Books Sales Meeting (Box 24)
    - 1974 Apr., International Direct Marketing Symposium, (4 folders) (Box 24)
    - 1974 May, Young & Rubicam stockholder meeting (Box 24)
    - 1975 Sept., Direct Marketing Idea Exchange (DMIX) (Box 24)
    - 1976 Jan., Direct Marketing Day, Montreal (Box 24)
    - 1976 June, Notes for Munich speech (Box 25)
    - 1976 Dec., New York University (Box 25)
    - 1977 Jan., Mail Order Association of Nurserymen (Box 25)
    - 1977 Feb., Young & Rubicam Affiliates, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - 1977 Mar., 4th Direct Mail/Marketing Association Conference, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - 1977 Apr., Managers Meeting, (4 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 25)
    - 1978 Apr., American Association of Advertising Agencies, (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 25)
    - 1978 Apr., General Foods seminar (Box 26)
    - 1978 Apr., Young & Rubicam Executive Committee (Box 26)
    - 1978 Nov., Young & Rubicam Arizona meeting, (3 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 26)
    - 1978 Dec., Ad Expo, (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 26)
    - 1979 July, Dartmouth/Geico seminar (Box 26)
    - 1979 Aug., Young & Rubicam Executive Committee, (4 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 26)
    - [1979 Sept., Direct Marketing/Mail Order Association: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8], (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - 1979 Oct., Direct Mail/Marketing Association, New Orleans (Ted Gordon speech), (1-4 of 10 folders) (Box 26)
    - 1979 Oct., Direct Mail/Marketing Association, New Orleans (Ted Gordon speech) (continued), (5-10 of 10 folders) (Box 27)
    - 1980 Jan., Idea file--Alvin Toffler The Third Wave in Playboy (Box 27)
    - 1980 Apr., Idea file--Walter McQuade article in Fortune (Box 27)
    - 1980 Apr., Montreux Symposium, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - 1980 May, Direct Marketing Idea Exchange (Box 28)
    - 1981, Frontiers of Direct Marketing (speech and booklet), (7 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 28)
    - 1981 Jan., Financial Communications Society (Box 28)
    - 1981 Feb., Advertising Research Foundation, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - 1981 Mar., Professors' Day (Box 28)
    - 1981 May, International Advertising Association (Box 28)
    - 1981 Sept., New York Times presentation (Box 28)
    - 1981 Sept., Young & Rubicam Resource Center Cassette of the Month, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - 1981 Oct., Direct Marketing/Mail Order Association (speech written by Lester Wunderman for Edward Ney, Young & Rubicam), (1 of 2 folders) (Box 28)
    - 1981 Oct., Direct Marketing/Mail Order Association (speech written by Lester Wunderman for Edward Ney, Young & Rubicam) (continued), (2 of 2 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1982, Business-to-Business Direct Marketing (speech and booklet) (Box 29)
    - 1982 Apr., Direct Marketing Day, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1982 Sept., Business Industrial Council, (4 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1982 Nov., Amsterdam speech (Box 29)
    - 1982 Nov., Hundred Million Club, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1983 Jan., Adcraft Club (Box 30)
    - 1983 Jan., Funny speech (not given), (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - 1983 Mar., Direct Marketing Association (Box 30)
    - 1983 Apr., American Marketing Association Chicago meeting, (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - 1983 Apr., Direct Marketing Day in New York, (7 folders)) (Box 30)
    - 1983 Apr., Young & Rubicam Resource Center Cassette, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - 1983 May, Canadian Direct Marketing Association Toronto meeting (Box 31)
    - [1983 July, Direct Marketing Day in New York: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8] (Box 31)
    - [1983 Sept., Direct Marketing Association--Miami: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8] (Box 31)
    - 1983 Nov., Direct Marketing Association Miami meeting, Frontiers of Direct Marketing II, (6 folders) (Box 31)
    - 1983 Nov., McGraw-Hill Telemarketing Conference (Box 31)
    - 1984 Jan., Semaine Française du Marketing Direct (Box 31)
    - 1984 Apr., Direct Marketing Association (Box 31)
    - 1984 Apr., Lincoln-Mercury Dealers Association (Box 31)
    - 1984 May, Montreux Symposium, Frontiers of Direct Marketing II, (9 folders) (Box 32)
    - 1984 Oct., Federal Trade Commission (Box 33)
    - 1984 Oct., RVI Seminar (Box 33)
    - 1984 Nov., Dublin speech (Box 33)
    - 1984 Nov., Time Inc. Direct Marketing Day (Box 33)
    - 1985 Feb., AJJC/Dentsu (Japan) (Box 33)
    - 1985 June, Australia speech, (3 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 33)
    - 1985 Sept., New Trends in Direct Marketing (Box 33)
    - 1985 Oct., Direct Marketing--A Many-Splendored Thing (Box 33)
    - 1986 Feb., French-American Foundation (Box 33)
    - 1986 Apr., The Future of Direct Marketing (Box 33)
    - 1986 May, British Direct Marketing Association (Box 33)
    - 1986 May, Canadian Direct Marketing Association (Box 34)
    - 1986 May, Electronic Shopping, (2 folders) (Box 34)
    - 1986 June, Deauville speech, (3 folders) (Box 34)
    - 1986 Aug., American Marketing Association--Chicago (Box 34)
    - 1986 Sept., Business-to-Business Direct Marketing (Box 34)
    - 1986 Oct., Finnish Marketing Association (Box 34)
    - 1986 Oct.-Nov., New Trends in Direct Marketing (Box 34)
    - 1987 Jan., ACCJ-Japan (Tokyo), The Worldwide Explosion of Direct Marketing (Box 34)
    - 1987 Jan., IBM--Tokyo (Box 34)
    - 1987 Jan., JAL (Japan Airlines)--Tokyo (Box 34)
    - 1987 Jan., Miscellaneous Japan speeches (Box 34)
    - 1987 Jan., NEC-Tokyo (Box 34)
    - 1987 Apr., Lester Wunderman Instituut (Amsterdam) (Box 34)
    - 1987 June, Direct Marketing Association, Cannes (Box 34)
    - 1987 Oct., Direct Marketing Association, New Orleans, (2 folders) (Box 34)
    - 1987 Oct., Lille Conference/Regional Development, (3 folders) (Box 35)
    - 1988 Jan., L.A. Direct (Los Angeles), (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 35)
    - 1988 Feb., Danish Marketing Association (Box 35)
    - 1988 Feb., Swedish Direct Marketing Association (Box 35)
    - 1988 Apr., PTT--Montreux (Box 35)
    - 1988 May, Postal Forum, Montreux, (1-2 of 5 folders) (Box 35)
    - 1988 May, Postal Forum, Montreux (continued), (3-5 of 5 folders) (Box 36)
    - 1992 July, British Airways talk (Box 36)
    - 1992 Nov., Action Marketing, Milan, (3 folders) (Box 36)
    - 1993 Feb., Rewrite of Milan speech (Box 36)
    - 1993 Apr., Apple talk, San Francisco, (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 36)
    - 1993 Oct., Direct Marketing Association, Toronto, (1-2 of 10 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 36)
    - 1993 Oct., Direct Marketing Association, Toronto (continued), (3-9 of 10 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 37)
    - 1993 Oct., National Infomercial Marketing Association (NIMA), (2 folders) (Box 37)
    - 1993 Nov., DIMA, Wiesbaden (Box 37)
    - 1993 Dec., Anderson Consulting (Box 37)
    - 1994 Jan., CADM Day, Chicago (Chicago Association of Direct Marketing) (Box 37)
    - 1994 Mar., Promotion Marketing Association of America, Chicago (Box 37)
    - 1994 Apr., Direct Response Television Expo, Los Angeles (Box 38)
    - 1994 June, DRTV-94, London, (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 38)
    - 1994 Aug., WCJ (Wunderman Cato Johnson) vision script (Box 38)
    - 1994 Oct., Paris presentation (Box 38)
    - 1995, Apple talk (Box 38)
    - [1995, Canada Postal conference: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8] (Box 38)
    - 1995 Mar., Insurance teleconference (Box 38)
    - 1995 Mar., New York University (Box 38)
    - 1995 May, Arrowwood, Which Way to the Future? (Box 38)
    - 1995 May, Barcelona speech (Box 38)
    - 1995 Sept., Brazil and Argentina talks (Box 38)
    - 1995 Sept., DMIX (Direct Marketing Idea Exchange), Yale Club (Box 38)
    - 1995 Sept., Germany speech, Which Way to the Future? (Box 38)
    - 1995 Nov., Canadian Postal Conference, Toronto, (3 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1996 Jan., Brazil, The Power and Future of Direct Marketing (Box 39)
    - 1996 Jan., Lisbon/Copenhagen, Which Way to the Future? (Box 39)
    - 1996 Feb., Mexico, Which Way to the Future? (revised) (Box 39)
    - 1996 Apr., IBM meeting, Sirmione, Which Way to the Future II? (Box 39)
    - 1996 Apr., USPS Seminar, Which Way to the Future II? (Box 39)
    - 1996 Sept., Women in Direct Marketing International (WDMI) (Box 39)
    - 1996 Oct., Direct Marketing Association, New Orleans, (2 folders; one folder removed to Oversize Materials Box OV8) (Box 39)
    - 1997 Apr., Hong Kong, Which Way to the Future? (Box 39)
    - 1997 May, Baden-Baden, Back to the Future (Box 39)
    - 1997 May, DMDNY (Direct Marketing Day New York) Lifetime Achievement Award acceptance (Box 39)
    - 1997 May, Newell conference, Which Way to the Future? (Box 39)
    - 1997 Sept., Boston/New York, Being Virtual in the Post-Present (Box 39)
    - 1997 Oct., Toronto, Being Virtual in the Post-Present (Box 39)
    - 1997 Nov., Brussels, Are We There Yet? (Box 39)
    - 1997 Nov., London, Which Way to the Future? (Box 39)
    - 1998 Jan., Retirement announcement, Exploring the Future (Box 39)
    - 1998 Apr., Seattle, Becoming Virtual in the Post-Present (Box 39)
    - 1998 May, Queen Elizabeth II, Data Alchemy (Box 39)
    - 1998 May, Vancouver, Welcome to the Postpresent (Box 39)
    - 1998 June, NYU Breakfast, Welcome to the Postpresent (Box 39)
    - 1998 Sept., Houston, Welcome to the Postpresent (Box 39)
    - 1998 Oct., Washington, Welcome to the Postpresent (Box 39)
    - 1999 Feb., Chicago, Advertising and Marketing in the Postpresent (Box 39)
    - 1999 Apr., Minneapolis, Advertising and Marketing in the Postpresent (Box 39)
    - 1999 Aug., Beijing conference (Box 40)
    - 1999 Nov., Anatomy of a Lead (Box 40)
    - 1999 Nov., Oracle Postal Service conference, Madrid, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1999 Nov., Publishing in the Postpresent (Box 40)
    - 2000, Breakfast with the Marketing Lab (Box 40)
    - 2000 Feb., New York Direct Marketing Club (Box 40)
    - 2000 Feb. 17, We Shall Never Cease from Exploration (Box 40)
    - 2000 June, The Most Elusive Word in Marketing (Box 40)
    - 2007, Consumer's Communication Bill of Rights (Box 40)
  - Speeches--Restricted Files, 1997-1999
    - 1997, Speech idea file (Box 41)
    - 1997 Apr., U.S. Chamber of Commerce seminar, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1997 Sept., Being Virtual in the Postpresent (Box 41)
    - 1997 Nov., Which Way to the Future? (Box 41)
    - 1998 Apr., Prudential Real Estate Business Conference (Box 41)
    - 1998 Apr., Web Marketing, Seattle (Box 41)
    - 1998 May, CAP Ventures, New York (Box 41)
    - 1998 May, Queen Elizabeth II, Marketing Forum, (4 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1998 May, Vision Conference, Vancouver (Box 41)
    - 1998 Sept., Direct Marketing Association, Houston (Box 41)
    - 1998 Oct., Direct Marketing Association of Washington (Box 41)
    - 1998 Oct., University Settlement Society, award acceptance (Box 42)
    - 1999 Feb., Chicago Direct Marketing Day (Box 42)
    - 1999 Apr., Alex Kroll/Bill Bradley (Box 42)
    - 1999 Apr., American Association of Advertising Agencies (Box 42)
    - 1999 Apr., IBM Seminar (Box 42)
    - 1999 Apr., Midwest Direct Marketing Association (Box 42)
    - 1999 Aug., Beijing conference, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1999 Nov, Publishing in the Postpresent (Box 42)
- Writings, 1946-2000 and undated, (17 boxes)
  Includes published articles and books, correspondence, drafts and proofs. Organized into two series: Articles and Book File. Articles includes materials relating to periodicals publications; Book File includes materials relating to Wunderman's book Being Direct: Making Advertising Pay. Where possible, original folder titles were retained. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Articles, 1969-1999
    - Advertising Age article, 1976 May (Box 43)
    - Adweek articles, 1983, (5 folders) (Box 43)
    - African Art of the Dogon (foreword), 1973 (Box 43)
    - [Book Promotion Can Sell More Books Caspar Pinsker Advertising, circa 1940s: Removed to Oversize Materials Box OV9] (Box 43)
    - Business-to-Business Direct Marketing booklet, 1983 (Box 43)
    - Business-to-Business Direct Marketing, Direct Marketing, 1983 July (Box 43)
    - Business-to-Business Direct Marketing: A Fundamental Strategy, Young & Rubicam Issues 17, 1983 (Box 43)
    - Comments on contest entries, Reporter of Direct Mail Advertising, 1969 Feb. (Box 43)
    - Complexity of Market Calls for Detailed Marketing Program, Reporter of Direct Mail Advertising, 1969 Mar. (Box 43)
    - De la idea a lost resultados, Alta Dirección, 1970 July-Aug. (in Spanish) (Box 43)
    - Delay Newsletter article, 1993 (Box 43)
    - Direct Marketing, Boardroom Reports, 1975 Mar. 15 (Box 43)